-- ==CMCT团队荣誉出品== --
字幕调校: wangbridge 影片压制: 蓝醉影
招募Q号: 76846146
T- minus ten, nine, eight, seven, six, five...
倒数计时 10... 9... 8... 7... 6... 5...
four, three, two, one, zero....
4... 3... 2... 1... 0 发射
Ignition.
火星任务
10... 9... 8... 7... 6... 5... 4... 3... 2... 1...
Ten, nine, eight, seven, six, fiive, four, three, two, one!
- Blast off! - Guys, guys, please, wait! Please!
- 发射... 发射... - 大伙儿 别吵我
This is very risky stuff here, and I'm a highly trained professional astronaut.
这是很危险的 我才是专业的太空人
- Here you go. - Now, Uncle Phil will launch another rocket...
- 给 - 让小费叔叔加满油
just as soon as he completes his fuel intake.
再发射另一枚火箭
Thanks, darlin'.
谢了 甜心
Now, you know, it takes six monthsjust to reach Mars.
光是到火星 就得花六个月
Then a year on the surface, six months back. It's, like, two years, you know?
待上一年 再花六个月回来 总共要两年
Anyway, guess what I'm tryin' to say here is that, um...
反正呢 我想说的是
you know, this bein' my last night on Earth and everything...
这是我在地球的最后一夜
this could be a very, uh, precious memory for me.
我想跟你拥有 一段珍贵的回忆
Nice try.
想得美
- William, get that thing out ofyour nose. - But I like it.
- 小威 别在鼻孔塞东西 - 我就要
- Don't you talk back to Mommy. - There you are.
- 不要跟妈咪顶嘴 - 你在这啊
- Hey, Woody. - Yeah?
- 伍迪 - 干嘛?
Our Mars One crew won't be heading back to Earth...
在你们的火星二号
till ten days afteryou guys land at our base camp with Mars Two.
登陆十天以后 我们的火星一号才会打道回府
- Uh-huh. - Oh, thank you, Renee.
- 哦 - 谢谢
That's a pretty good long rendezvous, don't you think?
十天的时间不短耶
- What are you suggesting, Sergei? - I think maybe you should bring a baseball bat.
- 瑟格 你有什么建议? - 我建议你带支球棒上去
- Yes, we will play American baseball on Mars, our two crews. - Oh, please.
- 咱们就在火星上打美式棒球 - 呃 好啊
- We could have ourselves a little solar system series. - Half you guys are foreigners.
- 两组队员在火星举办 一场太阳系杯棒球赛 - 你们都是菜鸟
- We'd crush you. - No, no, no, because we have equal crews.
- 我们赢定了 - 才怪 咱们旗鼓相当
We have three men, one woman. Same handicap.
都是三男一女 女人不会打球
Easy now. That's my wife you're talking about...
你可别小看了我老婆
and Terri just happens to be one hell ofa shortstop.
泰莉是很棒的内野手
Fast pitch, no steals, batter calls his own strikes.
硬式棒球不准盗垒没裁判
- Thousand bucks make it interesting? - Oh, winner take all.
- 赌金一千块钱 - 赢家通吃
Good. You bring the balls.
好 你最好带球来
You know the best thing about our mission?
这次任务最棒的是
On Mars Two, technically, I outrank her, so for the fii rst time in our marriage...
我在火星二号阶位比她高
she's gonna have to do everything I say, right, honey?
这次她得听我的命令 老婆 对吧?
- Yes, honey. - Yes, honey, sir...
- 对 老公 - 请你敬个礼
with a little salute helps.
顺便说声"长官好"
- Yes, honey, sir. - Yeah, I like it. It's good.
- 遵命 老公长官 - 我喜欢 好爽
- Take that corn up there, all right? - Yes, sir.
- 烤玉米棒拿上去 - 遵命 长官
I'm not sure how I feel about NASA allowing couples...
我总觉得太空总署
to go on this type of mission together.
不该让夫妻一起上火星
Well, nothin' personal, Terri. I mean...
我不是针对你
It... It'sjust that it's, uh... It's a funny feelin' for those of us stayin' behind.
只是我们留下来都觉得怪怪的
Yes, but you know that all the research shows that marriage will provide...
是的 但是根据研究显示...
stability on these long duration trips.
夫妻经过长期旅行 感情会变得更好
Then they haven't studied some ofthe couples I've known.
他们没有研究到我认识的夫妻
Luke. Come on, baby. He's not comin'.
路克 进来吧 他不会来了
This isn't right. I mean,Jim deserves this too.
这不公平 吉姆应该来的
- All of his friends are here. - I know.
- 他的朋友都在 - 我知道
- It's my last night here. - Hey!
- 这是我的最后一夜 - 嘿
It's your last night with us too.
你也应该陪我们呀
- I know. I'm sorry, baby. - Mm-hmm.
- 我知道 对不起 - 嗯嗯
- I love you, Deb. - I love you too.
- 我爱你 黛比 - 我也爱你
Maybe you should spend some time with Bobby.
你应该去陪陪巴比
- Yeah, where is he? - Up in his fort.
- 好 他在哪儿? - 在他的小城堡里
- Oh. Okay. - Millions of miles away.
- 好吧 - 几百万哩外
Deep space.
遥远的太空
So lonesome, so cold.
好孤单好冷清
So lame, Nick.
真差劲 尼克
Knock, knock.
敲敲门
Bobby?
巴比
Your friends are out there playin'. What are you doin' up here?
小朋友们都在玩 你一个人在这儿干嘛?
Who's gonna read to me now at bedtime?
你走了以后 谁替我读床前故事?
Your mother will.
你妈妈呀
But I like when you do it.
我喜欢听你读
- Now we're never gonna fii nish our book. - Bobby.
- 你走了就读不完了 - 巴比
Listen, I've been thinkin' about that too, okay?
这是个问题
And what I fii gured out was...
但是我在想
How about if I bring along my own copy?
我也把故事书带去
And then every night wherever I am I'll read a little bit more of it.
不管我在哪儿 我每晚都读一点儿
And you and Mommy, you can read a little bit more of it whereveryou are.
你跟妈咪也读一点儿
And it'll be kind of like we're reading it together.
就好像我们一起读一样
'Cause, hey, I don't know about you, but I'm kind ofanxious...
因为我也急着想知道
to fii nd out how old Ben Gunn got marooned on that island.
班甘怎么会漂流到金银岛
- You think that's a good idea? - Yeah.
- 这点子好不好? - 好
- Yeah? - Yeah.
- 好吗? - 好...
- 好? - 是的
Okay.
很好
Well, we were afraid you wouldn't come.
我们还以为你不来了呢
- I caught a whiff ofyour barbecue. - Oh.
- 我大老远就闻到一阵烤肉香 - 呵呵
- After that... - Yeah?
- 没办法... - 怎么?
I was, uh, helpless.
我就是抗拒不了诱惑
All the way out in Galveston?
你大老远就闻到香味?
- Somethin' like that. - Mmm!
- 像这样 - 是啊
It's his night, Deb. I didn't want to spoil it.
大伙儿在庆祝 我不想来扫兴
Spoil it? He has been going crazy lookin' foryou.
别胡说 路克一直在等你
Don't ever do that to me again.
下次别给我来这一套
- How ya doin'? - Hey. I'm doin' good.
- 你好吗? - 我很好
- Here. - Thanks, man.
- 送你的 - 谢了
A lot of people are gonna be mighty glad to see ya, you know that?
你来了大家都会很高兴
- Yeah. - Come on. Let's go in.
- 是啊 - 来 进去吧
You remember him?
你记得他吗?
- Come on. - Why don't you just let that go?
- 你就甭提了吧 - 你不该那样做的
(德州狄耿生市)
- As soon as you admit that it was a no-go situation. - It was a go situation.
- 你得承认这任务本来就行不通 - 当然行得通
Three months, no data stream, you're gonna land the ship anyway?
没有足够资料怎么登陆?
Just because you keep bringing it up doesn't make you right.
(公元2020年6月9日)你只是强词夺理
Just because you get loud doesn't make...Jim, settle it.
吉姆 你来说公道话
- No, no, don't... Don't look at me. - Settle it.
别把我扯进来...
- It's a go situation. - Well, th... this is exactly what I'm talkin' about.
- 这行得通 - 你太嘴硬了
- It's hard to admit. I know that. - Come on. Three commanders. One ship.
- 你死不认错 - 这叫一山不容三虎
I don't think that's gonna work.
就算太空船再大
There's not enough rocket fuel in the world to get those egos off the ground.
也容不下咱们这三个自大狂
- Come on. - Ah, we would have made a great crew.
咱们会是好搭档
- Maybe. If this man was left seat. - Yep.
只要让他当正驾驶
Guys, come on. I'm a... I'm a pretty good stickjockey.
少来了 我只是个机手
- You call me if you need a flight test. - What is a... What is a stickjockey?
- 模拟飞行找我就没错 - 什么是机手?
- l'm a pretty good stickjockey. - Come on, Mr Cover of Time Magazine.
- 我只是个机手 - 你上过时代杂志封面耶
The guy who landed a crippled Blockll shuttle.
是谁的太空梭迫降成功?
- Yeah. That's the stickjockey. - The stickjockey did that?
- 就是这位机手 - 什么机手嘛?
- Yeah, yeah, Mr StickJockey. - Okay, all right.
- 是的 - 好的
I made a little noise, but putting the fii rst footprints on Mars?
我是有点虚名 但是第一个登上火星?
That's for guys who wrote their Ph.D. thesis on how to colonize the place...
最好让路克 你这个外星殖民专家
and for guys who read too much science fiiction as a kid...
或是伍迪你这个 从小看科幻小说
- and still wear these little Flash Gordon rocket ships around their necks. - Yeah.
- 现在还挂着 火箭项链的老顽童去吧 - 是的
- Very, very mature. - Yeah, you read every damn science fiiction book I did.
- 老顽童 - 你看的科幻小说没比我少
And you'rejust not man enough to wear jewellery. That's all there is to that.
你只是没带种 不敢挂项链
- Give me it. - No, no, no. - Yeah. Take it. Get it.
- 给我吧 - 不 - 快抢过来...
You know you want Flash here. You ain't gettin' him! Oh, no!
我知道你哈了很久 你休想!
Yeah, Maggie would have loved to see you two clownsjust one more time.
可惜玛姬看不到你们这对活宝
I'm gonna go and get a beer.
我去拿啤酒
I don't know, Woodrow. I think it's about time you donated this baby to the museum.
你早该把这辆车捐给博物馆了
Internal combustion, boys. Accept no substitutes.
给我内燃式引擎 其余免谈
Jim, listen.
吉姆 听好
If there's, um...
如果你...
- If there's anything that Terri and I can do, you call us, all right? - I'm okay. I'm okay. Really.
- 要我和泰莉帮忙的话尽管说 - 我很好
- All right. - Thanks.
- 真的 - 谢了
- Luke. - Yep.
- 路克 - 是
I'll see you when I get to Mars. Listen. Don't solve all the mysteries ofthe universe, all right?
火星上见吧 别一个人解开宇宙奥秘
- Leave a little somethin' for the next guys. - I'm not promisin' anything.
- 给我们留口饭吃 - 我才不甩你
- You just bring some expensive beer. - All right.
- 除非带啤酒来 - 没问题
- Will do. Godspeed. - Thanks, buddy.
- 一路顺风 - 谢了 伍迪
It should have been your mission, Jim.
这本来是你们的任务
Yours and Maggie's.
你和玛姬的
Nobody ever wanted Mars the way you two did, not even Woody.
谁都没像你们这么想登陆火星 连伍迪也没有
You two were 1 2 years training for this thing, hoping for this assignment.
你们为了火星任务 受训了十二年
- It's... - Well, that's... That's all over now.
- 这 - 这都过去了
If Maggie hadn't gotten sick, if you hadn't pulled yourself...
如果玛姬没有生病
out ofthe rotation to take care of her, I mean, you...
你也没为了照顾她退出...
- Luke. Come on. - No, Jim. Wait a minute.
- 路克 别说了 - 等等
I want to say this.
我一定要说
Look, I wanted this assignment, all right?
我想要得到这项任务
But not like this,Jim.
但不是像这样子
I would give all ofthis up in a second if it would bring Maggie back to us.
我愿意放弃这一切 换回玛姬一命
I know that.
我知道
Look, all the years oftraining and planning for this mission have been a privilege.
我很荣幸 能为火星任务受训
Mars is yours now.
现在火星是你的了
Go get it.
去吧
I will.
我会的
You take care ofyourself, Jim.
你要保重 吉姆
You too, buddy.
你也是 老友
Okay.
好的
I'll see you when I get back.
等我回来再见面
Hey, Luke.
路克
Have a great ride.
玩得开心点
Always do.
我一向都如此
(十三个月后)
(火星 仙度尼亚区)
- Luke, do you read me? - Yeah, Renee.
- 路克 你收到吗? - 收到了 蕾妮
Luke, I just got ARES-8 on-line, and...
我刚刚和遥控探测器连线
Well, we... we think you're gonna want to see this for yourself.
你最好亲自来看看
Okay, copy that.
好 收到
- Now, is this a cinder cone? - No, it's too smooth.
- 这是火山吗? - 不是 太小太陡了
It's, uh, too angular. Volcanic upwelling maybe.
也许是火山丘
- No, no fiissure, no caldera. - No, it's an upwelling for sure, but maybe not volcanic.
- 不对 没有裂缝和破火口 - 这是个山丘 但不是火山
I mean, look at the colour and how shiny it is. That almost looks like...
它的表面光滑 看起来好像...
- It looks like ice. - This far south?
- 好像冰山 - 这么靠南边吗?
Impossible. You can't have ice at this latitude.
这种纬度不可能有冰山
I mean, not unless there's like a...
除非有...
- Okay, how far away is that? - Sixteen kilometres, northeast.
- 距离有多远? - 东北16公里
Take us 20 minutes to get there, Chief.
20分钟路程
Okay, we're gonna send a packet to Micker. We're going out there.
通知任务总部我们去看一看
- Keep working. - Okay.
- 好 - 继续观测
(世界太空站)
- Careful. Watch your step. - Yes, sir.
- 小心走 - 是的
- Is it possible to take picture? - Oh, picture.
- 可以照相吗? - 照相
- Come, please. - Let's have a picture.
- 当然可以 - 拍张相吧
Say cheese.
笑一个
This is a truly anomalous formation.
这是反常的现象
It's unlike anything everseen so far.
前所未见
The structure appears to be crystalline...
(火星任务指挥室) 这个形体
at least from the angle that's displayed by ARES-8.
看似水晶体
Now, we're trying not togo too nuts up here, but we think there's agoodchance...
(延迟20分钟) 我不想言之过早 但是...
that this could be an extrusion from some subsurfiace geothermalcolumn of water.
这也许是突出地面的冰柱形成
And, of course, if that's correct...
如果这是真的
then we may have foundthe key topermanent human colonization.
就有火星永久殖民的可能...
- We think it wise to suspend judgement here until we take our samples... - Let geology and hydrology know...
- 请地质学和水文学家进行分析
- and do a thorough investigation of the area. - we need to scramble on this, full-court press.
- 做一个彻底的调查 - 我们必须争夺这个
So we're gonna headout thereASAP and take a look at this thing...
我们会马上赶到现场进行勘测
try and get an idea of its composition.
并且确认它的成分
By the time you receive this, we should just about be on site.
当你们收到这讯息 我们应该就到了
Anybody else hearing that?
你们听到吗?
Yeah. What is it?
听到 那是什么?
I don't know. It sounds like, uh, interference from the rover.
不知道 好像是干扰杂讯
- Can you fiix it? - Hey, Skip, I can fiix anything.
- 能修好吗? - 老大 我什么都会修
Love that modesty.
你真是谦虚
Break out the radar. Let's see what this thing's made of.
用雷达分析这玩意是什么
Oh, yes, there's one more thing.
还有一件事
Now, this is a very important, very special day for a good friend of ours back home.
今天是咱们一个 好朋友的重要日子
We know he's there right now.
他一定在那儿
Now he hates it when anybody makes any kind of a fuss about him, so I'm not gonna mention his name.
他最讨厌大声张扬这件事 我就不说出他的名字
'Cause the last thing I would want to do would be to embarrass someone like Jim McConnell!
我可不想让你出糗 吉姆麦康纳
Was that loud? Oh, well, it's done now.
很大声吗? 没办法了
I mean, it can't be right. It says there's metal under there. Solid metal.
分析显示底下全是金属
No, that doesn't make any sense. You're reading a vein ofore, Renee.
这是不可能的 一定只是一条矿脉
No, it... It says it's under the whole mountain.
不是 整座山底下都是
All right. Move it closer, up the power, and we're gonna try it again.
靠近点 加强雷达再试一次
- Hey! - Happy birthday to you
- 嘿 - 祝你生日快乐...
Happy birthday to you
生日快乐
Okay, everybody, I want you to take a look at Jim.
来 大家看看吉姆
- Happy birthday, dear Jim - Now, is he all red with one of those fake...
- 他是不是脸红了 - 却假装自己开得起玩笑?
"Oh, I'm-a-good-sport"grins on his face?
他的脸上写着呢
- Happy birthday to you - That's right. Now, everybody, take... take a look at Ray.
- 生日快乐 - 大伙儿再看看老雷
Does he have one of those "This-wasn 't-in-my-mission-plan" looks on his face? Yeah.
他是不是一副受不了的样子?
Uh-huh. Thought so. Well, there's nothing you can do about it, Ray.
我们人在火星 你没辄了吧?
We're a hundred million miles away!
我们在千里之遥
Okay, let's blow it out.
吹蜡烛吧
- We're all set here, Chief. - All right, let's crank up the juice...
- 好了 老大 - 好吧 发射雷达
see what's in this sucker.
看看里面有什么
What happened?
怎么回事?
Oh, my God!
我的天
- You gettin' that, Sergei? - Uh-huh.
- 你录下来了吗? - 嗯
Oh, my God! Renee!
老天 蕾妮
Oh! Oh, my God! Oh,Jesus! Oh,Jesus!
我的天啊...
Problem: hatch door malfunction, backup power fail, manual override fail.
问题: 舱门故障 备用电源失效 无法开启
- Solution? - Replace optical relay.
- 解决方案? - 更换光纤输送线
Piece ofcake. God, who dreams up these nightmares?
小意思 这么简单的问题到底是谁想的
- Don't try to change the subject. - I'm not.
别顾左右而言它
- We're talking about your sister's wedding, right? - No, we're talking about...
- 才没有 你在说你老妹的婚礼 - 我们在说
- dancing lessons before my sister's wedding. - This is a nightmare.
- 我在说婚礼前 你说过要去上舞蹈课 - 噩梦啊
Do you mind? I'm in the middle ofa catastrophic power failure here. Check.
拜托 电源严重故障耶 马上检查
- Not effective. - Not effective?
- 无效 - 无效吗?
- Replace optical relay. - You're distracting me.
- 更换光纤输送线 - 都是你啦
Woody, we're a married couple. Would it kill you to invite me out on the dance floor just once in a while?
咱们都是老夫老妻了 你偶尔陪我跳跳舞会死吗?
- We danced. We danced at our wedding. We danced. - No. That's not dancing, Woody.
- 咱们在婚礼上跳过呀 - 那才不算跳舞
That's you shuffl ing your feet around while you grab my butt.
你只会踩我的脚摸我的屁股
I'm talking about real dancing, you know?
我说的是真正的跳舞
Cha-cha-cha, rhumba, jitterbug.
恰恰伦巴吉鲁巴...
Darling, face it. Some couples dance. Some go to Mars.
老婆 面对现实吧 别的夫妻跳舞 而咱们上火星
That's life. Test.
测验
Effective. Yeah. Woody, I'm serious.
有效
Just as soon as we get back home, we're starting lessons.
我是说真的你一回去就去上课
- Uh-huh. - Woody, if we never dance, people are gonna think there's something wrong.
- 呃 - 你不跳 别人就会说你有毛病
If they see me dance, they'll know there's something wrong.
别人看到我跳舞才会这么说
This is highly unprofessional.
你这样很不敬业哦
- This is highly unprofessional, sir. You keep forgetting that "sir." - Sir.
- 你要尊称我一声长官 你老是忘了 - 长官
Cockpit, this is Control.
机舱 这是指挥室
- Cockpit, this is Control. - Control, this is Cockpit.
- 机舱 这是指挥室 - 这是机舱
Yeah, Terri, it's Phil. They want us all to report to Micker ASAP.
我是小费 我们得马上到指挥室
- Who says to report to Micker? - The little men who live in my head.
- 谁说的? - 天上传来的声音
Well, that's a negative, Phil. We're in the middle of a catastrophic power failure right now.
不行 小费 这儿发生严重电源危机
Yeah, Woody, it was Ray Beck. He told me to round up the team. Now.
伍迪 马上来 老雷在召集所有组员
The exact same moment that we lost the data stream...
失去通讯的同时
they picked up this intense burst of energy from Mars.
火星表面发生强大的震动
- What do you mean intense? - Catastrophic.
- 有多强大? - 毁灭性
What about the crew?
队员呢?
The level of energy in the pulse didn't seem survivable.
以这么强大的震动看来他们无法幸存
How about the REMO?
补给太空船呢?
It went into Mars' or bit last week. Maybe it could give us some clue.
上礼拜进入火星轨道 也许有线索
That'sjust what we tried next.
我们查过了
All right. The, uh, resupply module checked out fii ne.
补给太空船一切正常
No instrument failures. Orbit holding steady, but there was something else.
没有损坏航道稳定 但是有一件事
The REMO's computer contained an uplink message...
上面的电脑包含一段讯息
a very faint, highly distorted transmission from Mars One base camp.
来自火星一号的基地
- Someone's alive. - Yes, yes, yes. Put up the message.
- 还有人存活吧 - 没错... 放吧
Still concentrating on the audio, but we've got a long way to go.
音讯不清晰 得花点时间修复
Show us whateveryou've got. Show us.
先放了再说
Ihave to make this... make this fast.
我的动作得快
I may not get another chance to... to make... another chance... chance...
要不然就没机会...
to the site... site.
回到事发现场
There was a low sound that...
有一股低沉的声音...
a low sound... sound... a low sound...
低沉的声音
Something came out of the top of the mountain, and it hit us.
山顶出现一个东西攻击我们...
And... it hit us... it hit us.
攻击我们
Oh, my God!
我的天
They're dead.
他们都死了
God! Nick... Man! They're dead.
尼克蕾妮瑟格 他们死了
That's it.
就这么多了
I don't know. Luke must be in pretty bad shape...
路克一定受了伤
if he hasn'tjust blasted out ofthere in the Earth Return Vehicle.
否则他会坐上紧急逃生舱
That thing's designed so even one crew member can fly it back to Earth.
就算只有一名队员 也能驾驶逃生舱
Even if Luke was in great shape, he couldn't get home.
就算他没受伤也办不到
An energy pulse ofthat magnitude would have fried the ERV's computers.
这么大的能量一定把电脑烧毁了
Other than the computers, how do we think the ERV fared?
逃生舱的状况如何?
Well, so far, our modelling says it should be in pretty good shape.
电脑显示它的状况良好
Which means it's gonna be up to us to get new motherboards...
我们尽快把
drives and software to Mars as fast as we can.
主机板和软体送去火星
- Right. - Slow it down. Slow it down. Slow it down.
- 好的 - 慢着... 慢着...
It's gonna take us weeks just to analyse this data.
光是分析资料 就得花好几个礼拜
Right, right, but in the meantime, we gotta be workin' up a mission plan.
没错 但是我们 必须准备救援任务
- Luke needs us now. - Luke may already be dead.
- 路克需要我们 - 路克可能已经死了
And even if he's not, it's doubtful he is going to be able to transmit again.
他就算没死也无法传讯
So we wouldn't know whether it's safe to land...
即使接近了火星表面
until we were almost there.
也不知道能不能安全登陆
What about SIMA?
SIMA呢?
What about SIMA? The Saturn imaging probe?
土星显像探测卫星
It's gonna slingshot around Mars on its way through the solar system.
它飞过太阳系时 会经过火星上空
It could be retasked to take pictures, read radiation levels of Mars One base camp.
它可以重新勘测 火星一号基地的状况
Wait, wait, wait. We are getting ahead ofourselves.
等等 别操之过急
You are forgetting the bigger problem. The orbits are all wrong.
问题很棘手 轨道全都不对
Our fii rst decent launch window is almost eight months from now.
最快要到八个月后才能出任务
Yes, but we can go earlier and get there faster...
没错 但只要 重新分配载货和燃料
if we reconfii gure the payload for extra fuel.
就能提前行动
We've modelled that, Ray. I've modelled it.
我做过电脑模拟 那只是纸上谈兵
On paper, yes, but those stresses have never been tested in space.
没有实际操作
- The ship can take it. - Oh, "ship can take it."
- 太空船承受得了 - 太空船能承受
I wasn't thinking ofjust the ship.
我担心的不是太空船
Ray, I know the protocols for a Mars recovery mission better than anybody...
我知道火星救援任务的规定
because I designed them.
那是我设计的
And I'm telling you, these guys can do it.
这些队员没问题
He's right, Ray. We got a real shot here.
他说得对 成功机率很大
Well, give me an updated mission plan by 8 tomorrow.
明天早上八点 把任务计划交给我
You'll have it by 6. Let's go to work.
我一早六点就给你 干活吧
- Chief, can I have a word? - Yeah, go ahead.
- 老板 我有事跟你谈谈 - 说吧
- I no longer have the right crew. - How do you mean?
- 我没有合适的队员 - 为什么?
Bjornstrom can be up here on the next shuttle.
贝斯壮可以搭太空梭赶来
Bjornstrom is a geologist. He's good, but not for this.
他是个地质学家不适合这任务
My peoplejust lost eight months of training.
我的队员必须马上行动
This is a different mission with a different objective.
这是一项救援任务
- I haven't approved the mission yet. - Yes, but when you do...
- 我还没有同意 - 但是你同意后
it ought to be given its best chance for success.
我必须有最佳人选
I want McConnell to fly right seat.
我要麦康纳当副驾驶
Oh.
哦
Jim McConnell is no longer on mission status.
他不在任务名单中
- Yeah, because you washed him out. - He washed himselfout.
- 你把他刷下来 - 是他把自己刷下来
He only had to pass a few more psych evaluations...
他只要接受几项心理评估
but he refused to take them.
但是他却不肯
His wife was dead. He didn't want to lay on a couch and share it with strangers.
他的爱妻去世 他不想跟心理医生谈
Yeah, that was his call, but I had to make one too!
那是他的决定 但这决定对我来说也很困难
It was tough as hell, but I'd do it again!
但是我并不后悔
For Christ's sake, Ray, she wasted away in front of his eyes.
她在他眼前死去
What was he supposed to do, suck it up? Get with the programme?
你要他怎样? 强颜欢笑吗?
What was his crime? That he... That he showed a little emotion?
痛失爱妻也有罪吗?
I couldn't trust him!
我不能再信任他
When Maggie died, it knocked the hell out of him.
玛姬的死对他是个很大的打击
It knocked the hell out of all of us.
对大家都一样
But you know and I know he's still the best we got.
但他是最好的人选
He and Maggie wrote the book on Mars.
他和玛姬对火星瞭若指掌
He's had more hours in the sims than the rest of us put together.
他的模拟经验比谁都多
We can do this, Ray.
我们办得到的
You give me McConnell as copilot, and we will bring Luke home.
让他去就能救回路克
It's a promise.
我保证
(火星救援号)
(任务第173日)
Hey. What's that?
那是什么?
That is the exact genetic composition of my ideal woman.
那是我的梦中情人
Hey, hey, hey. Hey!
嘿...
My baby.
我的梦中情人...
- Now what is it? - A frog?
- 现在这算什么? - 一只青蛙?
- Hey, Skip. - Hey. Take a look.
- 船长 - 你看看
Damn.
该死
- What do you make of that? - Dust storm.
- 你看那是什么? - 沙暴
Southern hemisphere, comin' from the east.
南半球 来自东边
It's a big fella too.
非常巨大
- Headed straight for Mars One base camp. - Yep.
- 直接扑向火星一号基地 - 是的
Could get a little hairy right about landing time.
我们登陆时会很危险
Yeah.
没错
Listen, we're gonna have to be able to move fast, maybe even advance our ETA.
我们的动作得快 也许必须提早行动
These bad boys can cover a whole planet and last up to a year.
沙暴会把火星遮盖 整整一年之久
- When does SIMA do her fly-by? - Tomorrow morning, 0600.
- 土星显影探测卫星几时到? - 明天早上六点
That's when we find out whether we've come all this way for nothin'.
到时候就知道路克还有没有救
My money's on Luke.
我打赌他还活着
Haveyouseen her so fine andpretty
Fooledme with herstyle andease
Andlfeelher from across the room
Yes it's love in the thirddegree
Ooh baby baby
Won'tya turnyourheadmy way
Come on take a chance You're old enough to
Dance
The night away
Whoa
Dance the night away
A live wire barely a beginner
Butjust watch that ladygo
She's on fire 'cause dancin 'gets herhigher
Than anything elseshe knows
Ooh baby baby
Won'tya turnyourheadmy way
All those interestedin dance lessons, please report to thepromenade deck.
想学跳舞的人请到舞厅报到
Dance the night away
Whoa
Oh
Oh oh oh oh yeah
And what, may I ask, brought this on?
请问这是怎么回事?
Zero G, my friend. My last chance to be graceful.
无重力 它让我成为舞王
Once we're in Mars' gravity, it's back to shuffl in' my feet and grabbin' her butt.
一旦登陆火星 我就只能踩她的脚 摸她的屁股
Dance the night away
Oh baby
Dance dance dance the night away
Oh come on dance
Incoming packet.
讯息传入...
讯息传入
It's SIMA.
土星探测器
Enhanced look at base camp.
放大火星一号基地
- Looks deserted. - It's still standing, though.
- 空无一人 - 但是它没事
So's the ERV. And, look, there's the greenhouse.
逃生舱还在 温室也在那儿
Well, we know Luke survived for at least a few hours.
路克至少存活了几个钟头
Now, are there any signs of recent activity?
最近有没有活动的迹象?
There. Scan northeastern quadrant of base camp.
那儿 扫描基地东北区
What the hell are those?
那是什么?
- Graves. - Wait a minute. There's only three ofthem.
- 坟墓 - 等等 只有三座
- That means that Luke's still gotta be alive. It means he's still down there. - Phil, no, no.
- 这代表路克还活着 他还在 - 不
It just means there was no one left to bury him.
这代表没有人替他埋葬
- Check the radiation levels. - Check rad levels.
- 侦测辐射量 - 侦测辐射量
Normal.
正常
- Go to disaster site. - Go to 41 by 9.
- 看看事发地点 - 显示座标41/9
- What's wrong? - I don't know. Magnetic interference?
- 怎么回事? - 不晓得 磁波干扰吗?
- Go infrared. - Switch to infrared.
- 用红外线 - 使用红外线扫描
It's gotta be a problem with SIMA.
一定是探测卫星的问题
I don't see how an earthquake six months ago could cause this kind of distortion.
不可能是六个月前的地震造成的
That was no quake.
那不是地震
We are going to continue analysing this data...
我们会继续分析资料
and try to determine what the problem is with those images.
查出这些影像的问题
We agree that the evidence of the graves is, uh...
我们同意光凭那些坟墓 也无法得到...
inconclusive...
确切的结果
and that aground search is advisable.
因此我建议进行地面搜索
Frankly, we are asstumped asyouguys, but we'llkeep on it.
老实说我也同样感到困惑 但是我们会尽力
Beware there are little sandstormskicking up...
目前又有一团沙暴...
- Bureau babble. - near Mars One base.
- 官方说法 - 逼近火星一号基地
But the big one youspottedis turning south.
但你们看到的大沙暴转南
It shouldn 't be a factor.
应该不是问题
We are pretty excited around here.
大家都感到很兴奋
Well, and we are sure you must be feeling the same.
你们一定也一样
- Enjoy your meal and get a good night's sleep. - Say it.
- 好好吃一顿睡个好觉 - 快说
- We anticipate... - Say it.
- 我们认为... - 快说
- that tomorrowmorning... - Say it.
- 明天一早... - 快说
you will be go.
你们就能出发
Yes! Yes! Thankyou! Thankyou!
好极了... 谢谢你 谢谢
Hooray for baby Jimmy!
吉姆宝宝万岁
Yes, Jim 's first spaceship wasseriously under powered.
吉姆的第一枚火箭 无法成功发射
Maggie was always a little star-struck.
玛姬一向都很爱追星
Come on. Show us those beautifulteeth.
秀一下你的大钢牙
I am gonna get you guys for that! I am gonna get you.
小心我要你们好看
When they met at the Air Force Academy, it was love at first flight.
他们在空军军校 是一飞钟情
- Woody's line. Woody's line. - Oh.
- 这是伍迪说的... - 哦
Later, during NASA training, thingsgot a little tough.
他们在太空总署受训时定情
Yes, Maggie always did keep Jim on a short leash.
玛姬老是爱把吉姆套牢
Jim was always trying to explore a heavenly body.
吉姆老是喜欢探索奥妙的天体
- Right. -Ah, yes.
- 好的 - 啊是
- Well, where are they goin '? Where are they goin '? - Ten thousand mile high club.
- 他们在干嘛? - 一万公里以外
- That's right. - Until...
- 对 - 直到
- Mission accomplished. - Oh!
- 任务成功 - 哦
Man, what a fun wedding. I was so whacked.
好棒的婚礼 我喝得烂醉
Uh, I'm going in. T-minus three, T-minus two...
倒数计时 3... 2...
T- minus one, contact.
1... 接触
Oh. Okay, we can stop it there.
够了 停下来
Stop there. Fast forward.
暂停 快转...
- All right. -And then what happened?
- 好的 - 怎么了?
I... Iknow what happened.
我知道发生了什么事情
- What nerves. - Okay, you guys.
好了 大伙儿
They're adding a wonderful chapter to their incredible story...
这是他们生命中的最新一页
and it's apretty historic one.
也是历史性的一刻
To the newly appointedco-commanders of Mars One, Jim and Maggie!
让我们敬火星一号指挥官 吉姆和玛姬
- Hear, hear. - I will drink to that.
- 注意 - 干杯
- Thank you. - Thank you.
- 谢谢大家... - 谢谢大家...
- Hold it. It's not over. - Show 'em. Show 'em. Show 'em.
- 还没有结束 - 秀出来吧
- Yeah, we got a little... a little addendum. - Oh, yeah, this is good.
- 我们漏了一样东西 - 一件东西
- Check this out, guys. - Here we go. It's Phil's best work.
- 你们看 - 这是小费的杰作 "来自火星的祝福
- Oh, yeah. - Look! It's Mars!
- 好的 - 瞧 是火星耶"
You can pick up these post cards at your locaI NASA souvenir shop.
请到太空总署礼品店购买卡片
You know, when you two land up there, it will prove once and for all...
你们登陆火星就能证明
that there really is no intelligent life on Mars.
火星上的生物没有智慧
- All right. Enough, enough. - Thanks a lot. Touche.
- 好了 够了 - 谢谢
- You're gonna eat those words. - I don't think so.
- 你说错了 - 才不
- Everett, give me the camera. -All right. - I don't think so. - Uh-oh, here we go.
- 给我相机 - 好了 - 这呢
- Let me take it away. - What? What if l'm right? - Here we go.
- 我拿走它 - 什么 - 这呢
- What if she's right? - Why does it have to be about us?
- 他要是对的怎么办 -
- You okay? - Why can't it just be about science? - Yes.
- 你还好吧? - 关于科学的吗 - 是的
- We'll do the science, and we'll do it really well... - Yeah.
- 人类科技已经发挥到极限 这是我们的训练 - 是
because that's what we've trained for.
因为我们训练过
But what if there's more? ln all our myths...
但也许宇宙不只有人类
in everyhuman culture, Mars has always helda specialattraction.
在人类的每一种文化中 火星都有特别的意义
I mean, what if that means something?
也许这代表了什么
The universe is... is not chaos. It's connection.
宇宙并非混沌 一切都有关联
Life reaches out for life.
生命在寻求别的生命
That's what we were born for, isn 't it?
这不就是人生的意义吗?
To stand on a new world and look beyond it to the next one.
站在新世界寻找另一个世界
It's who we are.
这就是人类的使命
You know, she may have been right.
也许她说得没错
If that wasn't a quake down there, then something else caused it...
如果那不是地震 就是什么造成的
or planned it.
或是计划的
You thinkin' the same thing?
你一定也这么想
It's never been out of my mind.
我一直都这么想
I think she knew something, Woody.
她一定知道什么
She was the only one of us who ever really believed...
只有她相信火星上有生物
there might be something down there.
下面可能有什么东西
Yeah, well, we're not leaving until we fii nd out. Deal?
找不到解答我们就不走 好不好?
Deal.
好
Range: 67-83 and closing.
距离6783 接近中
65 minutes until Mars orbital capture.
65分钟后进入火星轨道
Okay, people, let's look sharp now. We're gonna run this simulation one more time.
大伙儿 打起精神 咱们再模拟一次
Remember, if we overshoot, there's no comin' back.
千万记住错过轨道就回不来了
Yeah, and drifting through eternity will ruin your whole day.
永远漂流在外太空绝对不好玩
Okay, Delta-V systems initialized.
启动加速系统
Charge primary APU.
打开主要辅助电源
Engaged and charged.
打开了
- Select HPU fuel cells for run. - Engaged.
- 准备运转液压电瓶 - 使用中
- Tie main bus to systems. - Power ready.
- 连接主汇流板 - 准备好
Select H2O2 HPU and fuel cells for open.
打开二氧化氢燃料阀门
H2O2 fuel valves open.
二氧化氢燃料阀门打开了
Charge flow.
输入燃料
Charged and on-line.
输入无误
- Reset PW. - Set.
- 重新调整电波 - 好了
Transfer protocol data from EVA station.
输入救援程序资料
Transferred. Awaiting track confii rmation.
好了 等待确认
Jesus! Oh!
天啊
Micrometeoroids.
微流星体
Kill those alarms!
把警报关掉
Critical systems alert. Critical systems alert.
系统严重受损...
- Breach hits in the hull. - We're out gassing, losing pressure.
- 太空舱破裂 - 我们失去气压
Woody, seal the breach. Looks like it's behind Jim's helmet.
伍迪 快去补洞 看来在吉姆的头盔后面
Ninetypercent atmosphere.
仅存九成空气
Criticalsystemsalert. Criticalsystemsalert.
系统严重受损...
We're losing pressure fast. We're gonna decompress!
我们很快会失去舱压
Computer, how long till zero atmosphere?
多久会完全失压?
Fourminutes, nineseconds.
4分9秒
We're still outgassing in the lower hab.
下半部还在漏气
There must be another hole down there. It's gotta be a big one.
一定还有一个洞 一定很大
Everybody switch to suit oxygen. Jim, you've got the ship.
大家戴上头盔 吉姆 你指挥
- I'm going EVA. - Copy.
- 我要到外面 - 重复
Come on, people. Let's work the problem.
大伙儿快想办法 收到
Eightypercent atmosphere.
仅存八成空气
Jim, you got to go get your spare helmet.
吉姆 你得戴上头盔
Copy that,Jim?
你听到吗?
There's no time. All the systems have crashed.
来不及了 系统全部当机
I gotta shut down the hab from below.
我得关闭生活舱
We're losing pressure, Jim. You could embolize.
严重失压你的血管会爆裂
Seventypercent atmosphere.
仅存七成空气
Phil, you've got to get the nav computers back on-line.
小费 快把导航电脑接回来
Uh,Jim, I've got an idea.
我有个点子
If you guys can save enough atmosphere...
只要你储存足够氧气
I'll disconnect the power in the main computer bay and jump-start the systems.
我就把主电脑关掉 然后再重新开机
- I'd basically be doing a hard boot. - Has that been tested?
- 我得切断电源 重开机 - 有人试过吗?
Are you kidding? These machines are way too expensive.
别开玩笑了 设备这么贵 谁试得起?
- Do it. - Okay. I think this will work.
- 去做吧 - 好 我觉得一定行
Sixtypercent atmosphere.
仅存六成空气
- Jim, how we doing on the AG? -Just hang on one second, Woody.
- 吉姆 能不能关掉重力? - 等一下
- Fifty percent atmosphere. - Come on.
- 仅存五成空气 - 快
- Come on. -Jim, I've got oxygen.
- 快 - 吉姆 我这儿有氧气
- Come on. - Voiceprint identification.
- 快 - 声音辨识
- Mc...McCon... - Not accepted.
- 麦康纳 - 不接受
Voiceprint identification.
声音辨识
- McConnell! - Accepted.
- 麦康纳 - 接受
Shut down gravitational rotation.
关闭重力旋转
Shutting down artificial gravitation alrotation.
关闭人工重力旋转
Jim, I've got the oxygen for you.
吉姆 我有氧气
- Hang on! - Forty percent atmosphere.
- 等一下 - 仅存四成空气
- Are you okay? - Yeah, yeah, I'm fine.
- 你没事吧? - 我没事
- I'm topside,Jim. Do you know which sector? - I'm working on it.
- 我在上面 破洞在哪儿? - 我正在检查
- You better get some oxygen,Jim. - Yeah. Yeah, I'm fine.
- 你最好快戴上氧气罩 - 好 我没事
Come on.
快点
Jesus.
天啊
It's like lookin' for a needle in a haystack.
这简直就是海底捞针
Okay, come on.
快啊
Come on. Where are you, you little bastard?
臭东西 你在哪儿?
Give me some light on the hull so I can locate it.
把灯打开好让我看到破洞
I got a better idea.
我有更好的点子
Gotcha.
有了
Terri.
泰莉
Squeeze out the liquid.
把汽水挤出来
S- Stay there.
别过来
- Squeeze it out. -Jim.
- 快挤出来 - 吉姆
Okay. Okay. Please work.
好 一定要成功
Thirty percent atmosphere.
仅存三成空气
Woody, the breach is between sectors fiive and six.
伍迪 破洞在五六区之间
- Five and six. Do you copy? - Copy. I'm headin 'there now.
- 五和六区 收到吗? - 重复 收到了 我正赶去
Son of a bitch. You never did that in a simulator.
乖乖 这种事哪有模拟过?
- Twenty percent atmosphere. - Jim?
- 仅存二成空气 - 吉姆
- Tenpercent atmosphere. - Jim!
- 仅存一成空气 - 吉姆
Jim, talk to me. It's Terri.
快说话 我是泰莉
- Jim. - Come back.
- 吉姆 - 快回来
- Breathe! - Come back!
- 呼吸 - 回来
Gotcha.
好了
Pressure stabilizing. Pressure stabilizing.
舱压稳定中...
- Jim? - Twenty percent atmosphere.
- 吉姆 - 恢复二成空气
Hi. Welcome back.
嗨 你醒了
Thirty percent atmosphere.
恢复三成空气
It worked! Yes! It worked!
成功了 好极了
Way to go, everybody. All right! Yeah!
干得好 大伙儿 好耶
There's a lot of scarring out here. I'm gonna check for other punctures.
有很多擦痕 我要继续检查
Orbitalinsertionproximity alert. Orbitalinsertionproximity alert.
警告 接近火星轨道...
Negative, Woody. That is a negative. You have to get back inside.
不行 你得进来 我们得准备进入轨道
We have to do our checklist for orbital insertion.
我们必须做入轨的清单
Copy. I'm on my way.
收到 我进来了
Hello, beautiful.
小美人 我来了
Prepare to initiate burn. Prepare to initiate burn.
准备启动引擎...
Okay, we're ready to light this candle.
咱们准备点蜡烛了
Go/No go for braking burn and MOl.
进入轨道前检查
- Engines. - On-line.
- 引擎 - 连线
Go.
可以
- Systems. - On-line.
- 系统 - 连线
Go.
可以
- Nav. - On-line.
- 导航系统 - 连线
- Go. - We are go for the burn.
- 可以 - 准备启动
I am fuelling engines.
输入燃料
Flow chargeron-line. Flow charger activated.
燃料管连线 进行输入
Optimum angle ofen try in minus seven degrees.
最佳轨道角度 负七度
Countdown to initiate burn for or bitalinsertion.
启动引擎 开始倒数计时
Orbitalinsertion proximity alert.
接近火星轨道
- Four. - Optimum insertion angle approaching.
- 4 - 接近最佳轨道角度
Jim?
吉姆
Optimum insertion angle imminent.
即将进入最佳轨道角度
- One. - Let's go to Mars.
- 1 - 咱们登陆火星吧
Jesus!
天啊
- Attitude incorrect. - Shut down the engines.
- 角度错误 - 快关掉引擎
Engines negative. No response. I have got no attitude control.
引擎没有反应 我无法调整角度
- Manual separation. Blow the bolts. - Negative. The control module...
- 手动分离下半部 - 发射指挥舱
doesn't have enough thrust to correct this rotation.
也无法调正角度
We're too steep. We're falling into the atmosphere.
角度太大 会冲进大气层
Christ, at this angle, we're gonna burn up.
以这角度下降会被烧毁
- How much time we got, Phil? - I don't know. Three minutes? I don't know.
- 有多少时间? - 不晓得 三分钟
- Where's the REMO? - The resupply module? Why? There's no way we're gonna be able to link up.
- 补给太空船呢? - 找它干嘛? 我们无法和它连结
Where is it?
它在哪儿?
Resupply module located. Resupply module located.
找到补给太空船...
- It's close. - How close?
- 很近 - 多近?
- I don't know. That's gonna take some time. - Figure it out.
- 我得花点时间计算 - 计算出来
We don't have time, Phil. Figure it out now.
没时间了 快点计算
Jim, we're dead stick. There's no way to manoeuvre this ship into linkup.
我们无法把太空船开过去
Not the ship.Just us. We go EVA.
不开太空船 我们自己飞过去
- You want us to transfer in suits? -Jesus, Jim, if we don't make it...
- 只穿太空衣? - 天啊要是错过就完了
- If we miss the REMO... - There's no other choice.
- 如果我们错过补给太空船 - 别无选择了
- Phil, how close? - Intersection orbit with REMO.
- 它有多近? - 拦截补给太空船
Course intersectionplotted.
算出拦截航道
One kilometre. That's the best I can do.
一公里 我只能用猜的
Prepare to abandon ship.
准备弃船
Let's go!
快点
- What are you looking for? - Earth.
- 你在找什么? - 地球
Hey, when we get back home, we really will have to try this out in the sim.
等我们回到地球 一定要在模拟室试试看
How we doing on the fuel, Woody?
燃料还剩多少?
I'm at 50 percent. I don't see the REMO.
我只剩五成 我没看到补给太空船
There it is. Forty-fiive left, forty-fiive down.
在那儿 左45度下45度
Oh, Jesus. She's not where I thought she'd be.
天啊它比我想像的远
- We're gonna miss her. - What do you think?
- 一定会错过 - 你觉得呢?
We can't catch it. Not like this.
这样不是办法
Use the tether. You'll have one, maybe two shots before she's out of reach.
用缆绳 我们有一两次机会
Negative. It's too risky. Ifwe miss her, we got nothing.
太冒险了 万一错过就完了
I'll leave you the gun. Run a line out to the REMO.
抓好了 我去勾住它
I got enough fuel left for that.
我有足够燃料
- You'll be going too fast. - I'll aim to overshoot.
- 你会撞上它 - 我要飞越它上面
Brake like hell and arc it in. Piece ofcake.
勾住了就用力抓住它 小意思
I'll see you in a flash.
回头见
Unhook me.
把我解开
Good to go.
好了
Okay, I'm on a path to overshoot. I'm gonna take the edge off.
我会飞越它 我要先减低速度
I'm out off fuel. Coming in hot. Still long.
燃料用完了 速度很快 还是太快了
"警告"
Abandoning the unit. I'll break with suitjets.
抛弃推动器 改用太空衣引擎
Jesus. Jesus.
天啊天啊
Suitjets gone. I'm gonna make contact.
太空衣引擎失效 我就快到了
- What velocity? - Impact's gonna be a little rough.
- 时速多少? - 冲撞力会很大
- At what velocity? - Thirty-two.
- 时速多少? - 32公里
- I'm gonna use the gun to slow you. - No.
- 我把你扯慢一点 - 不行
- If you slow me, I'll fall short. - It's too fast, Woody.
- 这样我抓不到它 - 你太快了
No choice. I'll be okay. Here we go!
没办法 我没问题 来吧
Gotcha.
勾到了
Woody!
伍迪...
伍迪!
Woody! Woody!
伍迪... 伍迪...
Woody. Woody.
伍迪
- No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no. - Woody. Woody.
- 不... 不... - 伍迪
- Terri. - Woody.
- 泰莉 - 伍迪
Take the gun. Take it.
拿着枪 拿去
Phil, hang on. Go.
小费 抓紧了 去吧
Woody, what's your status?
伍迪 你的状况如何?
Well, uh, my suitjets are gone, and I'm still carrying a good deal of velocity.
太空衣失效了 我的速度还是很快
Soon as we get hooked up, I'll come get you.
等我们勾住了就去救你
- I'd have to say negative on that,Jim. - Negative on the transmission?
- 吉姆 不行 - 你的收讯不清楚吗?
No, I heard you. Negative on the manoeuvre. I am not retrievable.
不 我听到你 你不能这么做 我没有救了
- Woody, you're not going that fast. - Well, it all comes down to the amount offuel, honey.
- 你的速度并不算快 - 你们的燃料不够
Suitjets are designed for attitude control, not travel.
太空衣不是用来飞行的
- Retrieval just won't work. - Well, it's gotta work.
- 你们救不了我 - 一定行的
Hey, listen. I don't like it any more than you do.
听好 我也不想要这样
- Woody. - Run the numbers,Jim.
- 伍迪 - 吉姆 算出燃料量
I am.
正在算
You hang tight, Woody.
撑着点
We'll get in the REMO, drop her down and come scoop you up.
我们会开补给太空船去救你
- Sounds good,Jim. - It's gonna take us halfan hour to get the REMO reoriented.
- 好吧 - 启动太空船得花半小时
Woody will be in the atmosphere by then.
他早就冲进大气层了
- Then we'll just have to get her moving faster. - We don't have time.
- 那么我们就得快一点 - 来不及了
Listen to Jim, honey. It's a good plan.
听吉姆的话 这是好主意
No. We're gonna come get you.
不 我们要去救你
- Okay. Get ready for brakes. - Come on, now.
- 准备减速加油 - 快点
- On my mark. Three... - You can do it.
- 我数到三 3... - 你们办得到
- two... - You can do it! - one.
- 2... - 加油! - 1.
- Come on! - Mark! - Come on!
- 拜托 - 马克 - 拜托
Yeah!
耶
- Everybody good? - We're on, Jim.
- 大家没事吧? - 我们勾住了
Way to go. Way to go.
干得好
Good job.
很好
All right. There won't be enough room for us inside.
太空船的空间不够
Soon as I get the hatch open, let's start dumping the cargo.
我一打开舱门 就开始丢东西
- Copy that. - Hang on, Woody.
- 收到 - 伍迪 撑着点
Will do,Jim.
我会的
Hello, beautiful.
小美人 我来了
Come on.
快点
All right. It's open.
打开了
- Terri, no! - Terri! Come back!
- 泰莉 不! - 泰莉 回来
You'll never make it!
你救不了他的
- Terri, what are you doing? - I'll tell you what I'm not doing, Woody.
- 你在做什么? - 我知道我在做什么
- I'm not gonna watch you die. - Terri.
- 我不能看着你死 - 泰莉
You'd do the same for me.
换作是你也会这么做
Phil, get inside, dump the cargo and start the systems. Now!
小费 快进去 启动电脑系统 快点
- No, I wouldn't. Not if it was impossible. - I can do it!
- 我不会白白送命 - 我办得到
No, you can't. You don't have enough fuel to come get me and get us back.
你没有足够燃料来救我
Listen to me, goddamn it. You have to stop, and you have to stop now.
听我说 你得马上停下来
He's right, Terri. It's no use.
他说得对 没有用的
Okay, honey.
好了
You gotta go back now.
你得回去了
The hell I do.
我才不回去
What are you doing?
你在干嘛?
I'm gonna jet in a little closer and try again.
我要飞近一点再试一次
Terri, you spend any fuel getting closer, you won't get back.
你再浪费燃料就回不去了
And ifanyone tries to get you, they'll die too.
别人来救你也会没命
Honey, please. Please go back.
求求你 回去吧
Go back and help the others to the surface.
回去帮助他们
I am not losing you!
我不要失去你
I can't let you do it.
我不能让你这么做
- I can't let you die. I'm sorry. - Woody.
- 我不能让你死 对不起 - 伍迪
What are you doing?
你在干嘛?
- Love you, honey. - Woody...
- 我爱你 - 伍迪
No. No!
不!
- God, how I love you. - Woody! Don't!
- 天啊我好爱你 - 伍迪 住手!
Woody! Woody!
伍迪
Woody! Don't! No!
别这样 不!
No! Please, God, no!
不! 天啊不要
Woody.
伍迪
Come back, Terri.
回来吧 泰莉
- He's gone. - No.
- 他死了 - 不...
No.
不...
- Terri. - No.
- 泰莉 - 不
We need you.
我们需要你
Woody.
伍迪
No.
不
No. No.
No.
不
Please, Terri.
求求你
Come back.
回来吧
Ray. We've got some new data just coming in.
我们收到新的资讯
We just... It doesn't make any sense.
没有道理
We're not sure how to read this.
我们真无法解释
- Data? - Yes.
- 资讯? - 是的.
Telemetry reports the REMO left its orbit and reached the Martian surface.
他们说补给太空船 脱离轨道登陆在火星上
- Crashed? - No, sir. Under power.
- 它被撞毁了? - 不是 它自行降落
- What? - Sixty-three minutes after Mars Recovery went off-line.
- 什么? - 救援太空船断线63分钟后
Sir, the graph shows a controlled descent...
补给太空船就开始下降...
but that doesn't make any sense.
这一点都没道理
They used the REMO as a lander.
他们把补给太空船当成登陆艇
It's... It'sJim McConnell. It's got to be.
一定是吉姆的点子
Nobody else could have pulled this off. Nobody else.
没有别人办得到
Son of a bitch.
这个好小子
I've got access to the ERV. I'm gonna go inside.
我打开逃生舱 我要进去了
Terri, is the oxygengen erator okay?
泰莉 供氧系统能用吗?
Yeah. It's gonna take a while to get back to 1 00 percent capacity, though.
能用 得花点时间才能完全运作
Okay, I'm entering the hab.
我要进入生活舱
There's still oxygen in here.
里面还有氧气
This is a little spooky.
有点恐怖
I don't like the dark at all.
我有点... 怕黑
Need some lights. Need some lights.
我需要灯光
Okay. Where are we?
在哪儿?
Here we go.
这儿
ERV appears to be structurally intact.
逃生舱的结构似乎无碍
Yeah, butjust as we thought, the computers are fried.
没错 电脑被烧坏了
Copy that.
收到了
I got busted fii lters here. Clogged intakes.
滤网坏了 油管堵塞
Hell ofa cleanup job, but so far no major damage.
挺麻烦的 但是不算严重
I'm in the greenhouse.
我在温室
- You gotta see this. - What is it,Jim?
- 你们得来看看 - 怎么了?
It's working.
温室正常运作
I'll be damned.
不可思议
- Luke. - No!
- 路克 - 不
You're not here! You are not here!
你不存在! 你不存在!
Your wife is Debra. Your son is Bobby.
你老婆是黛比 儿子是巴比
- No! - You're reading Treasure lsland with him.
- 不 - 你念"金银岛"的故事给他们听
Luke...
路克...
It's all right. It's me.
没事了 是我
- Jim? - Yeah.
- 吉姆? - 对
No, wait! No! No, no! Wait, wait!
不 等等...
He's all right. He's all right.
他没事 他没事
Phil? Phil.
小费?
Terri.
泰莉?
Jim...Jim, what are you... what are you...
吉姆 你在这儿干嘛?
What are you doing here? You're not supposed to be...
你怎么会在这儿?
You're not supposed to be here. How are you here?
你不应该在这
- How are you here? - This is a rescue mission.
- 你怎么回到这来? - 这是救援任务
Woody wanted me right seat.
伍迪要我当副驾驶
I can't...
我...
I can't believe...
我不敢相信
Well, where is he? Where's Woody?
他呢 伍迪呢?
He didn't make it.
他死了
God.
上帝
Oh. Oh.
哦
Oh, no, no.
哦 不
Oh, God. Oh, no.
天啊不...
Well, it works, you know? I give them...
这很好 我给它们...
CO2 and light, and...
光和水
they give me oxygen and food.
它们给我空气和食物
It's... It's actually not a bad arrangement, you know?
这样的安排不错
It's kind of like a marriage, really...
我们有点像夫妻...
except not as many... not as many fii ghts.
只是不常吵架
- I mean, some fii ghts. - Luke. Tell us what happened here.
- 比较少啦 - 路克 发生什么事?
I...
我
We fii red the radar...
我们一发射雷达波...
and it... it came, and they all died.
它就出来把他们杀死
They all... They all died.
他们全都... 死了
Wh-What do you mean? What... What came?
什么意思 什么出来?
The force came out ofthe top ofthe mountain and-and-and...
那股力量从山顶出来
everybody died, but I was spared.
大家都死了只有我活着
Why? Why?
为什么?
Had to be for a reason.
一定有原因
And then all of a sudden, I knew the reason why.
后来我突然想到原因
It's so someone would be left to fii gure out the secret.
一定要有人活着解开秘密
You know? It's...
你们懂吗?
J- J-J ust come.Just come, come, come, come, come, come.
来吧 来... 来...
Is itjust me, or is he a few meal packs short ofa picnic?
你们有没有觉得 他的脑袋好像有点问题
Long-term exposure to low gravity can have an adverse impact on the brain.
长期在低重力状态 会影响大脑功能
Or then, he could be suffering from some form ofasphyxia.
他也可能患了缺氧症
Or maybe his whole crew died, and he's been marooned alone on Mars for a year.
他的队员全部罹难 他被困在火星整整一年
It's a miracle he's survived this long.
他能活这么久已经是个奇迹
I'd better bring him up to speed.
我最好跟他谈谈
Great, great. Great, great, great, great.
好极了... 好极了...
So let me be sure I understand this.
让我搞清楚
Your ship blew up with all its supplies.
你们的太空船和补给全都爆炸
Then you... Then you emptied all the cargo out ofthe REMO...
丢光补给太空船的东西
and it was to talled on landing.
登陆时又把它撞毁...
You got no food, no water, no, no spare oxygen.
没有食物清水氧气
Nothing other than what I'm looking at right here.
除了我眼前的这些
What kind... What kind of rescue mission is this,Jim?
这算哪门子的救援任务?
That kind.
这一种
Check it out. New nav boards for the ERV.
你瞧瞧 全新的导航主机板
I got four round-trip tickets, baby, right in here.
四人的来回机票全在这儿
Thankyou, God! Oh, thank God.
感谢上帝 谢天谢地
When I came to and dug myselfout ofthe sand, my faceplate was cracked.
我清醒后就爬出来我的面罩破裂.
It was leaking. Leaking badly.
开始漏氧 很严重
I barely made it back to base.
我差点回不了基地
It was weeks before I could work up the nerve to go back out there and look for...
过了好几个礼拜 我才鼓起勇气回去...
and look for their bodies.
寻找他们的尸体
Renee was the only one I could find, but it just didn't seem right somehow to just dig one grave.
我只找到蕾妮的尸体但是只挖一个坟不太好
Oh, God.
天啊
Has it been blowing like this for a while?
风沙吹了有一阵了吗?
Yeah.
对
We saw a big storm on our screens, but Micker said it was turning south.
我们侦测到一团大沙暴
If it holds course.
只要它继续前进
Luke, this... this whatever it was.
不管那是什么.
This... This force.
这股力量
You said it came directly out ofthe top of the mountain?
它是直接从山顶冒出来吗?
Don't you believe me?
你不相信我?
That's okay,Jim. You don't believe me, that's okay, but I'm not crazy.
你不信 没关系 但是我知道我没发疯
- I know that much. I'm not crazy. - What'd you mean by its "secret"?
- 我知道我没发疯 - 你说的秘密是什么意思?
What secret?
什么秘密?
Listen, hundred of millions ofyears have gone by, okay?
火星存在了亿万年
You got erosion, lava flow, sandstorms, meteor impacts.
经过地表侵蚀火山爆发 还有陨石撞击
Hell, in that much time, the whole surface ofthe planet would have changed.
地形一定完全改观
So it's no wonder we never saw it before.
所以我们没看到那东西
I mean, we saw it, but not like they meant us to.
我是说我们看见了
- There was too much dirt on it. - Saw what, Luke?
- 因为它被土堆覆盖住了 - 看到什么?
Saw this.
这个
Jesus.
天啊
Oh, my God. Luke, what are you trying to tell us?
哦 天啊路克 你到底想要告诉我们什么呀?
- You're trying to tell us that that's a face? - That's the face.
- 你想说那是一张脸吗? - 是的.
It's the face. It's real.
那是一张脸 这是真的.
Somebody put that thing there, and it's not us.
这玩意可不是人类放的
Jim...
吉姆...
It's not possible.
这是不可能的
Jesus.
老天
Look at that. My God.
你看看 我的天
I know.
我知道
Luke, uh, what...
路克
what about that sound you heard before the explosion?
你听到的声音呢?
Oh, yeah. Good,Jim. Th-Th-That's the key. That's the key.
没错 那就是关键
- You hear that? - Yeah.
- 听到吗? - 是的.
- It's pauses. Do you hear the pauses? - Yeah.
- 你们听到那些间顿吗? - 是的.
See, that's what made me realize it's a pattern.
我发现这声音有规律
It's a repeating pattern.
这是重覆的模式
- Mathematical? - Mm-hmm. That occurred to me too.
- 数学模式吗? - 我也这么想
There are distinct blocks within each pattern...
每个模式都有段落...
and within each block, the tones come in groups ofthree.
每个段落有3组声调.
It's three, three, three, three, three, three. It's always three, three, three. It's always the same.
3组... 3组... 永远一样
And, see, for months I struggled to analyse it, you know...
我花了四个月分析它的结构...
trying different constructs, and then I thought about dimensions.
后来我想到次元
- X-Y-Z coordinates. - Exactly. Three groups equals three dimensions.
- XYZ座标 - 没错 三个次元
So l-l assigned different graphic values to each block group and tone...
我为每组声调画出不同的图表...
and I came up with this.
结果就是这个
- Hello. - Oh, my God.
- 哈罗. - 我的天.
- Is that what I think it is? - DNA?
- 这是我想的吗? - DNA?
- You see it? - Yeah.
- 你们看到吗? - 看到
- It's a model of DNA. - So... So somebody left that thing here.
- 这是一组遗传基因 - 有一种生物把它留在这儿
Okay. Somebody other than human.
肯定不是人类
But, uh, what is it?
这是什么?
It's a signature.
这就像签名
It's a self-portrait ofwhatever species created the face.
也就是这些外星人的自画像
Yeah, but, uh, that DNA looks human.
但是... 这看来像是人类
- No. - No, it's not. It's missing the last pair of chromosomes. See?
- 不. - 不 缺了最后一对染色体
- This is close. It's damn close. - "Close"?
- 但是很接近 不是吗? - "接近"?
The difference between man and ape is less than three percent genetic material.
人类和人猿的分别 只有3%的遗传基因
But that three percent gives you Einstein, Mozart.
也就有了爱因斯坦莫札特
Jack the Ripper.
和杰克开膛手
Yeah, he's right.
他说得没错
Four pallets, oral, topical medications...
口服液药膏...
splints, bandages, one complete med pack.
夹板绷带急救箱
With eight tubes ofantifungal cream.
还有八条益可肤
Well, at least we won't rash to death.
至少我们不会起湿疹痒死
Luke. How do you feel?
路克. 你觉得怎样?
Lighter. A lot lighter.
轻爽多了
- Welcome back. - Thanks, man.
- 欢迎归队 - 谢了
The backup generator is salvageable. So are two of the solar panels.
备用发电机和太阳能板都能用
I'm pretty sure I can get the oxygen still back into production.
我也能修好供氧系统
So we're not in such bad shape, considering.
情况还不算糟
That's good, Terri.
很好
Good work.
干得好
Jesus.
天
Look at this. Phil's idea ofabsolute essentials.
你们看 没有这些小费就活不下去
Ofcourse.
是啊
Hey, hey, hey. Hey!
嘿
My baby.
我的梦中情人
- It's not a signature. - What?
- 那不是签名 - 什么?
The noise from the face. It's not a signature.
人脸传来的声音不是签名
It's a test.
那是个测试
It's asking us for the right answer.
它要我们给正确答案
It wants us to put in the missing pair of chromosomes.
我们得补齐遗缺的一对染色体
Why?
为什么?
To prove that we're human.
证明我们是人类
We fii red radar into that thing, concentrated radio waves, and you're saying...
我们向它发射雷达音波
Which it interpreted as the wrong answer.
它认为你们答错了
It's... It could be like a security alarm.
也许那就像保全系统 你答错了...
When it gets an incorrect response, it defends itself.
它就会自卫
So what happens when it gets the right answer?
要是答对了呢?
Well, I don't know that, Phil.
我不知道
But we gotta fii nd out.
但是我们得试一试
Luke, what ifwe work this the other way?
能不能倒过来?
We fii gure out which tones would be equivalent to the missing chromosomes...
算出遗缺的染色体的声调...
and then dub them into your recording ofthe signal.
然后录进那段声音里面
- Is that possible? - Yeah.
- 可以吗? - 是的.
- Yeah, I think so. - Good, good, good.
- 应该可以 - 很好
What about the radar gun? Will it accept the input so we can transmit a completed signal back to the face?
雷达枪呢? 能不能向人脸传送完整的讯号
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa. Hold on,Jim. What ifyou're wrong?
慢着 要是你错了呢?
Whoever goes out there...
不管谁去都有危险
I mean, what ifyou're wrong? Three people have already died over that thing.
三个人为这玩意送了命
Four.
四个人
Terri.
泰莉
If we leave here without getting some answers, they all died in vain.
要是我们找不到答案就走 他们就白白送了命
We don't...
我们
We don't have to go out there.
我们不必去那儿
Got a lot ofstatic here. Something's interfering.
受到干扰 杂讯很多
Yeah. The antenna got knocked around pretty badly in the blast.
是啊那次的爆炸把天线撞歪了
This is the best resolution I think we're gonna be able to get.
这是最好的影像
All right, guys. I got the nav boards. I'm sealing the airlock.
好了 导航系统装好 我要封闭舱门
- Check the video feed. - Video feed looks good.
- 检查影像讯号 - 看起来不错
- How close do we have to get? - I'm not sure.
- 到底要多近才行? - 我不确定
Maybe I'll stop it right over there by that rock.
我在那块石头旁边停下来
Do it. Good.
好吧
Okay. Here we go.
好了 来吧
Look at that,Jim.
你看看
It worked. Oh, God, it worked.
成功了 天啊成功了
Guys, I don't know what the hell we just did...
我不知道我们做了什么...
but does that look to you like a hostile gesture?
不过那看来像是有敌意吗?
No. More like an invitation.
不像 倒像是一种邀请.
Or another test.
或是另一个测试.
- Check for radiation. - Normal.
- 检查辐射量 - 正常.
Seismic: Normal. Anemometer: Steady.
地表震动正常 风速稳定
Luke...
路克..
does the rover still work?
越野车还能用吗?
Phil, do you read?
小费 你收到吗?
Uh, yeah,Jim, your signal's breaking up a little in the storm, but I read you.
收到 有点杂讯 不过我收得到
We're at the face.
我们在人脸前面
We're gonna need a few minutes here. Same deadline.
我们需要一点时间 一样的时间
Launch at 1 950 with or without us. Copy?
无论如何都要 七时五十分出发 收到吗?
Copy that.
收到
Jim. You sure you wanna do this?
你确定要这么做吗?
I'm not sure about anything any more.
我什么都不能确定
But I didn't come 1 00 million miles just to turn back in the last ten feet.
但是到这个地步 我不会临阵脱逃
Yeah.
好
Please work.
一定要成功
It's gonna work.
要成功
Yes. Yes. Computers are on-line.
好耶 电脑连线了
I am gonna start loading software.
我要开始安装软体
The surface...
表面...
seems firm and level.
看起来坚硬平整
Roger that.
没错
The texture's smooth.
非常光滑
I've got good footing. No obstructions.
我走得很稳 没有障碍
- Let's check our PSl. - Okay.
- 检查一下气压 - 好的.
Guys, I gotta tell you...
大伙儿
we're losing visibility here really fast. Over.
这儿的视线越来越不清楚
It's solid. We're trapped.
这是实心的 我们被困住了
Don't move. Just keep this orientation.
别慌 不要乱动
Guys?
大伙儿?
Luke? Terri?Jim?
路克 泰莉 吉姆?
Phil, can you still hear me?
小费 你听到吗?
Is anyone there? Over.
有人在吗?
God. That's it.
没办法
There's no handles. We're not getting out of here unless they let us out.
没有门把 我们出不去 除非他们让我们出去
- Jim. Jim, what are you doing? - Jim, what are you doing?
- 吉姆 你在干嘛 - 吉姆 你在干嘛?
- Jim. Jim, your suit! - Stop. Stop it! Jim, you're depressurizing.
- 吉姆 住手! - 住手 吉姆 你正在减压
- Seal your suit. - Come on! - Seal your suit now!
- 快把衣服装好 - 快把衣服装好
There's pressure in here.
这儿有气压
Above Mars atmospheric? It's impossible.
比火星的气压还高? 不可能
We're millions of miles from Earth inside a giant white face.
我们在火星上一张人脸里面
What's impossible?
有什么是不可能的?
There's 1 2 PSI in here.
气压是12psi
Nitrogen and oxygen.
有氮气和氧气
Otherwise known as air.
也就是空气
Hey, wait, Jim. I haven't checked for let hal trace gases, and I haven't...
等等 我还没检查有没有毒...
What the hell.
管它的
Look.
你们看
- That what I think it is? - Yeah. It's Mars.
- 这是我想的吗? - 没错 那是火星
That's where they went.
他们逃到那儿
Look. One stayed behind.
瞧. 有一个留下来
Earth, before the continents separated.
那是五大洲 还没分离之前的地球
My God. That's it.
我的天 没错
Hundreds of millions ofyears ago...
亿万年前
there was a sudden explosion of life on Earth.
地球突然有了生命
The fii rst multi-celled plants and animals appeared.
出现了多细胞植物和动物
No one has ever understood why or how it happened.
没有人知道原因
They seeded Earth.
他们在地球播了种
They're us.
他们是我们
We're them.
我们就是他们
Luke? Terri? Jim? Anyone?
路克 泰莉 吉姆? 有人吗?
ERV to rover. Rover, this is ERV.
呼叫越野车 有人收到吗?
Does anyone copy? Does anyone copy?
呼叫越野车 收到吗?
ER Vto rover. Rover, this is ER V. Doyou copy?
呼叫越野车 有人收到吗?
- Phil? - Oh, thank God, l got you.
- 小费? - 谢天谢地
- Phil, we read you. - Listen, the storm is getting bad, really bad.
- 我们收到了 - 沙暴越来越大
It's gonna totally sock us in in a few minutes. You've got to get back to the ship.
我们会被吸走 你们得回来
- Phil? - I repeat, you've got to get back to the ship.
- 小费? - 重覆 赶快回来
Phil?
小费?
We're in a ship.
我们在太空船里面
This is a ship.
这是一艘太空船.
And the count down's already started.
倒数计时开始
- He's right. - Yeah.
他说得对
Yeah, let's... Iet's get the hell out of here.
我们快走吧
Jim?
吉姆?
Jim.
吉姆
Come on. We gotta go.
我们得走了
- I'm not coming with you. - What?
- 我不跟你们去 - 什么?
What are you talking about?
你在讲什么?
We've gotta get home.
我们得回家
That's where I'm going.
我要回家
Don't you see?
你们不明白吗?
That's... That's what all this is for.
这是他们的目的
Terri, you were right. This is an invitation.
你说得对 这是一种邀请
This is an invitation for us to follow them home.
他们邀请我们跟他们一起回家
I'm going.
我要去
It's what I was born for.
这是我的命运
Like Maggie said:
就像玛姬说的
"To stand on a new world and... and look beyond it...
站在新世界迎接
to the next one."
另一个世界.
I know this is right.
我知道对我来说...
For me.
这是对的
And you're running out of time. You gotta get back to the ERV and you gotta get off this planet.
你们来不及了 快上越野车离开火星吧
Thank you for saving my life, buddy.
谢谢你救我一命
It was a privilege.
这是我的荣幸
I wish Woody were here to see you.
我真希望伍迪在这儿
He is here, Terri.
他在这儿 泰莉
We wouldn't have made it without him.
没有他我们就来不了
He would have wanted you to have this.
他一定会把这个送给你
ERV to rover. Rover, this is ERV. Do you copy?
呼叫越野车 这是逃生舱 收到吗?
ERV to rover. Rover, this is ERV. Do you read me?
呼叫越野车 你们收到吗?
Phil, this is Luke. Do you copy?
小费 这是路克 你收到吗?
- He's not reading me. - I can barely read you.
- 他听不到我 - 我都听不到你
- Let's get the hell out of here. - Yeah.
- 快走吧 - 好.
I've lost the base camp beacon. We're driving blind.
没有基地的引导信号 无法辨识方向
I'm just gonna keep going on a straight line, okay? That's our only chance.
我要直直地往前开 这是唯一的机会
- 1 949. Terri, we're not gonna make it. - No.
7时49分 赶不到了
I've worked with Phil for fouryears, and I knowJim gave him a direct order, but he is not gonna leave without us.
我认识小费四年 他不会把我们抛下来
Please. Luke?
拜托 路克
Terri? Jim?
泰莉 吉姆
ERV to rover.
呼叫越野车
Rover, this is ERV. Do you read me?
这是逃生舱 收到吗?
Phil, do you read? This is Luke. We're coming in. Phil.
小费 收到吗?这是路克 我们来了
- Phil! - Phil isn't here right now.
- 小费... - 小费不在家
He, uh, left for Earth fiive minutes ago!
他五分钟前就回地球了
Please leave a message after the beep!
听到哔声后请留
Where is Jim?
吉姆呢?
He caught another ride.
他搭另一艘太空船
- Dear God, look at that. - Is that him?
- 老天 你们看 - 那是他吗?
Have a great ride, Jim.
一路顺风 吉姆